hey guys this is one of the most
requested videos I've ever had and for
good reason this is such a cool problem
I did not expect it to have the outcome
that it had so the problem gives us a
semi-circle right here and a quarter
Circle right here and then this red line
with the length of five that goes from
the vertex of this rectangle tangent to
the semicircle if you want to try this
on your own pause it right now because
I'm going to solve it in three two one
so first up let's assign a radius to
this semicircle a lot of people wanted
to assign this radius to match but there
really is not evidence that this radius
is the same as this radius so let's call
it something else like X using our
method we're not going to need this
radius to equal this radius and that
right there is one of my favorite things
about this problem we don't care if the
radii are the same so this last distance
right here will also be R because it's a
radius of the same semicircle and this
height will also be X because it's a
radius of this quarter Circle and now we
can come up with a formula for the area
of the rectangle the area of a rectangle
is base times height the base is going
to be equal to X Plus 2R and the height
is going to be equal to X and then we
can distribute this x x times x is going
to give us x squared and x times 2R is
going to give us 2xr and this is a very
nice formula for the area for the next
step let's draw a segment from this
point of tangency to the center of the
semicircle and this distance is also a
radius of the semicircle so it's going
to be R this right here is going to be a
right angle every radius that intersects
a tangent line at the point of tangency
is at right angles so now we have a nice
right triangle so we can do Pythagorean
theorem r squared plus 5 squared equals
the quantity X plus r squared we can
bring down the r squared 5 squared is 25
and X plus r squared means X plus r
times X plus r and after we multiply
that out we get x squared plus 2xr plus
r squared and then we can subtract r
squared from both sides on the left hand
side we have 25 and on the right hand
side we have x squared plus 2xr and now
we're pretty much done we wanted to know
what is the area of the rectangle but we
know that the area is equal to x squared
plus 2xr so we can plug that in right
here but we also know that X squared
plus 2xr is equal to 25 so we can change
this to 25 and that's the answer to our
question let's give it a label of
centimeters squared and put a box around
it even if these radii are not equal to
each other we can find the area of this
rectangle is exactly 25 centimeters
squared how exciting Isn't that cool